

Samy CHBINOU

DevOps Engineer

Imp Juan, ANTIBES, FR

06 67 89 55 87

samy.chbinou@esna.cloud

https://chbinousamy.github.io/resume/resume.pdf

English, Italian, French

BACKGROUND

ABOUT

51 years old, Telecom & Software engineering education, I worked in software industry on real time embedded applications for mobile phones, IP multimedia set top boxes. Lately I did Proof of Concepts for Cloud Native infrastructure platforms for Machine Learning, called MLOps, That is DevOps for Machine Learning applications.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Career Break, Relocation, Antibes 06

Oct. 2021 - Present

DevOps, NAVYA, La Défense 92

Sep, 2021 - Oct, 2021 1 month

NAVYA Drive delivers autonomous driving. In a Agile team of 5 persons I added Gitlab pipelines automation for Continuous Integration Tests. I also setup some Gitlab runners to handle load CI tests. Directly installed on Bare Metal and on some VMs, Virtualbox and AWS

o CI pipelines on Gitlab runners

- Docker Buildx Python Containers
- MaaS SRE
- Terraform on local VMs and AWS

Artificial Intelligence Engineer, VALEO, Créteil 94

May, 2021 - Jul, 2021 2 months

Valeo. In the transversal GEEDS entity, I assist in relocation of the R&D Datacenter from Paris to Créteil.

- Buildx Nvidia Docker Containers
- Assistance in relocating a Datacenter from Paris to Creteil

Platform Engineer, Nokia Bell Labs, Nozay 78

Oct, 2014 - Dec, 2020 6 years 2 months

Nokia Bell Labs. Cloud RAN Entity, a private Cloud for Radio Access Networks which connects radio devices, UE, IoT, Automotive, Virtual Reality. I worked as freelance in a 'StartUp Garage'. I setup a small hardware platform to make some tests on different types of technologies: storage databases, ethernet over fiber, docker containers and kubernetes clusters, Machine Learning DevOps pipelines

- o n-Tiers Architectures: Docker, Kubernetes, Databases, Private Cloud and ServerLess platforms
- Machine learning and Neural Networks Data engineering
- o Benchmarking CPU Offloading on Nvidia GPU, FPGA
- Benchmarking Ethernet over Optical Fiber (RDMA)

Software Test Engineer, Ercom, Thales Subsidiary, Vélizy 78

Apr, 2006 - Apr, 2013 7 years 1 month

Ercom is a Thales Subsidiary. I worked in a 10 people Télécom team on Mobipass product, a Functionnal and Stress Test for eNodeB and 4G/LTE Mobiles. As Software engineer, I developped a User Interface in .NET C# language and did many tests on Network Data Encoding and Decoding.

- Integration and Validation Tests
- Network Data Blocks Encoding and Decoding
- C#.NET UI software development
- Functionnal and Stress Tests of eNodeB and 4G/LTE Mobiles

SKILLS



EDUCATION

	Telecom and Software Engineering, Engineer, IMT Atlantique (ex Télécom Bretagne) Sep, 1994 - Jun, 1996				
INTERES	-S				
Open Source					
Photograph					
DIY					